# Rui**C**osta Software Developer



# contact

Rua Laureano Brito,№5 Casa 1 4910-519 Vila Praia de Âncora Portugal

> **(**+351) 924 241 327 S rui.d.a.costa

ruidacosta in ruidcosta

### languages

Portuguese mother language English & Spanish fluency French basic (A1)

#### programming

JavaScript, C++, PHP, Java, C#, PL/SQL, Pvthon, CSS & HTML5, Golang,

#### frameworks

NodeJS, AngularJS, JQuery, Django

#### tools

Salite, MySal, Oracle, MongoDB, Git, SVN, Docker Part Time

# presentation

A versatile and professional graduate software developer with 6 years of commercial experience. Worked with C++, C#, Javascript and PL/SQL on Windows environments. Unix and Unix-like user with 10+ years of personal experience.

A proven ability to maintain and enhance company software with the aim of improving operational functionality in line with business requirement.

Able to work with any technology and to perform full software development life cycle activates.

Looking for a software developer opportunities that will allow me to work alongside an expert team of developers and on challenging projects in terms of technology and implementation. Thereby helping to drive my career progression to more seniors roles in the future.

### experience

#### **Full Time**

### 2017-Now Natixis on Behalf of GFI - Software Developer

Work directly with business analysts, located in Paris and London, in order to implement client needs. Develop new features in existent applications (Squall and Booster) used by clients to book and manage contracts of SLB (Stock Lending and Borrowing) and TRS (Total Return Swaps). Create executables to generate specific client reports in csv files, and sending then by FTP or directly by email. Develop and manage communication on gateways with external SLB exchanges. Maintenance on existent applications, correcting bugs and optimising code. Second line support on Sophis Front Office - Equities and Commodities. Key Skills: C#, C++, Oracle Database, SQL Server, WPF, Windows Batch Scripting, SVN, TFS, Sophis, Equities, Commodities

Porto, Portugal

#### 2013–2017 **Finantech - Software Developer**

Porto, Portugal Build functions and procedures on Oracle Databases for all company's trading systems. Add features, using C#, on a software designed to enable clients to configure their business rules. Fix bugs on trading server-side software, using C# and C++. Maintain existing libraries for communication interfaces with market data providers updated, using C++. Develop a Web Interface for all server side trading systems, using AngularJS and JQuery on front-end and C++ on backend. Server side application to insert real-time market data on a DB2 database system. Support clients in European and American financial markets. Key Skills: C++, C#, Oracle Databases, HTML, Javascript, JQuery, AngularJS, DB2 Databases, Fix Protocol, HTTP, REST API, Multi-Threading

#### 2006-2010 Freelancer - Backend developers

Develop back-end for some small websites in PHP. Key Skills: PHP, MySQL, Apache, HTML, Javascript

# education

2010–2013 **Incomplete Master** of Software Engineer Specialization in Network and Distributed Systems. Thesis missing

2006–2010 **Bachelor** of Software Engineer

University of Porto, Portugal

University of Porto, Portugal

## interests

**professional:** software development, software design, web app creation, real-time computing, high-throughput computing, high-performance computing, parallel computing **personal:** riding motorcycle, playing music, cooking, trekking, spearfishing